# Mariaclaudia Nicolai

Pharmacy student and passionate about technology



### About

I am an Italian pharmacy student with knowledge in both chemistry and biology. I built my pharmaceutical background by studying at the University of Salerno. After the curricular internship in the pharmacy, I started working on my experimental thesis. I focused on the identification of a novel antimicrobial peptide activity model using machine learning algorithms. Meanwhile, I collaborated with TU Delft for a research project. Finally, to express the passion for technology, I co-founded the LPSystems B.V., a company specialized in designing embedded devices.

# Personal info:

#### **Contacts**

Via San Leucio 82100 Benevento Italy +39 349 12 00 304 mariaclaudia.nicolai @gmail.com

### **ORCID**

0000-0001-9270-8564

## **Publication indexes**

https://Google Scholar

### Languages

Italian: Native speaker English: Good

# **Highlights**

09.2013	MSc. in Pharmacy	University of Salerno
present	Thesis subject: Identification of a novel	Italy
	antimicrobial peptide activity model by	
	machine learning and its use to build new	

peptide sequences

07.2018 Visiting (research) TU Delft Research subject: Role of users' feedback 05.2019 The Netherlands

on healthcare mobile Android apps

05.2018 Internship (curricular) Farmacia Dr. Italiano

Internship subject: Ethical and deontological 11.2018 Italy aspects of the profession of pharmacist and

> applications of the notions acquired during the study

2015 **Collaboration** (work) Bruitparif Work subject: Manual handling of precision 2016 France

electronic tools

# **Education**

2013-present Master degree in Pharmacy (31 of 32 exams)

Organization University of Salerno, Italy

> Thesis "Identification of a novel antimicrobial peptide activity model by machine

learning"

Tutor Prof. Dr. Stefano Piotto

## Grants

2015-2016 **Scholarship** 

# **Internship**

05.2018-11.2018 Internship (curricular)

Farmacia Dr.Ugo Italiano s.a.s. Benevento, Italy

Tutor Dr. Stefano Italiano

### Scientific research

Workshop WAMA 2019 "Healthcare Android Apps: A Tale of the Customers' Perspective"

In Proceedings of 3rd International Workshop on App Market Analytics

Presented at ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference Tallinn, Estonia

# **Work experience**

2015-2016 Collaboration

Bruitparif Paris, France

Company details Bruitparif is a non-profit environmental organization responsible for

monitoring the environmental noise in the Paris agglomeration

Contribution Testing of electronic devices, handling precision electronic tools

2019-present Co-founder

LPSystems Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Company details LPSystems B.V. designs low-cost professional audio broadcasting equipment

# **Acquired skills**

Software skills

Languages Python, HTML

Tools GMDH, YASARA, KNIME, LaTeX, Git, PyCharm

Lab skills

Lab techniques Conducting and supporting scientific investigations and experiments

Planning, setting up and undertaking controlled experiments and trials

Recording and analyzing data, demonstrating procedures

Presenting results to senior staff

Writing reports, reviews, and summaries

Good teamwork skills

Equipment Safety goggles and safety equipment

Beakers, flasks, funnels, graduated cylinders, droppers, pipettes,

thermometers, Bunsen burners, balances